<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

	<h3>July 8<sup>th</sup> 2014, 6:30 P.M.</h3>
		<br>
		<h4>Janavasam</h4>
		<p align="justify">
			Janavasam is the Tamil (notably TamBrahm ) equivalent of a North Indian Baraat. It is customary for the bridegroom to travel to the wedding venue, accompanied by his family members. On their arrival, they are garlanded by the Bride's family and are served refreshments because foood, that's why. This is done to the accompaniment of traditional music.
		</p><br>

		<h4>Nischayathartham</h4>
		<p align="justify">
			This ceremony is a commitment to the forthcoming wedding an announcement to the community. Five 'sumangalis' (married ladies) pound a handful of 'urad dal' (lentils) on a dry grinding stone decorated with flowers, <a href = "http://www.flickr.com/search/?q=Kumkum" target = "_newtab">Kumkum</a> and <a href="http://www.flickr.com/search/?q=turmeric" target="_newtab">Turmeric</a>. This is done to symbolically wish the couple a happy married life. Also because TRADITION, MOFO!
		</p><hr><br>
	<h3>July 9<sup>th</sup> 2014, 9:00 A.M.</h3>
		<br>
		<h4>Varadham</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			This ritual marks the commencement of all wedding rituals. The groom's hair is anointed with oil and he showers using soap-nut powder, except this time where the groom will definitely only shower using Old Spice. The bride goes through a similar ritual. She changes into a new sari and is made to sit down for the 'muth aarthi'- a traditional '<a href = "http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aarti#Practice" target = "_newtab">aarthi</a>' performed for her with a lighted <a href="http://www.flickr.com/search/?q=diya" target="_newtab">'diya'</a> , 'kumkum' and flowers.
		</p><br>

		<h4>Kaasi Yatra</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			The groom makes an attempt to proceed to <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/i2mHb" target="_newtab"> Kaasi</a> to "pursue further religious studies" (Wikipedia's words, not ours). The bride's father intervenes and advocates for the superiority of married life to an ascetic life. He also promises the groom his daughter as a companion to face the challenges of life. The groom accepts and returns to the wedding venue to get married.
		</p><br>

		<h4>Oonjal</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			The couple sits on an "Oonjal" or swing (because ain't nobody got time for a rollercoaster), which is rocked gently. The swing's oscillating motion is a message to the couple that they must stay strong together during the challenges and joys of life. Relatives and friends sing auspicious songs, blessing the couple.
		</p><br>

		<h4>Kanya Dhaanam</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			 The bride and groom hold hands and re-enter the wedding venue after their wild oonjal ride. They hold on to a coconut dipped in turmeric, onto which the bride's mother pours water. The bride is seated in her father's lap all through this ceremony. The bride's parents pray to the Lord to bless the couple. This may also be used as a demonstration of the hydrophilic properties of a coconut dyed yellow.
		</p><br>

		<h4>Mangalyadharanam</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			The highlight of the marriage is the Mangalyadharanam where the groom ties the sacred '<a href="http://www.flickr.com/search/?q=Maangalyam" target="_newtab">Maangalyam</a>' on the bride as she is seated on the lap of her father. The groom holds the 'thaali' in his hands and recites a religious verse. He then ties it around the neck of the bride, he makes the first knot and the two others are completed by his sister. The three knots symbolize Brahma, Vishnu and Rudhra. Flowers are showered on the couple as a blessing.
		</p><br>

		<h4>Sapthapadi</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			The couple walk around the sacred fire. The groom walks with the bride to the right side of the sacred fire while holding his wife's right hand. He stops, bends down and holds the right toe of his wife with his right hand and helps her take seven steps around the fire. At the beginning of each step, he recites a Vedic mantra seeking the blessings of Maha Vishnu. As these seven mantras are being chanted, he asks Maha Vishnu to follow in the footsteps of his wife and bless her with food, strength, piety, progeny, wealth, comfort, a yacht and health.
		</p><br>
		
		<h4>Reception</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			Food. Music. People. The fun stuff.
		</p><hr><br>
	<h3>August 16<sup>th</sup> 2014, 6:30 P.M.</h3>
		<br>
		<h4>Party in Seattle</h4>
		<p align = "justify">
			The fun stuff, Take #2.
		</p>